Ok. Now, that Myra's hair is sectioned off and I'm ready to apply color I want to mix my color. You don't want to mix your color too early.
Because, it actually starts the color process at that time.
So, in my bottle I have nothing but my hair color.
This is after I've been to the store, chose the right color.
And, this actually has measuring lines on the bottle itself.
So, I'm going to follow my measuring lines.
Apply my developer, which now once you apply the developer the color starts to process.
Put your cover on.
Make sure you cover the opening with your finger.
And, you want to lightly shake this.
You don't want to be too vigorous with it.
Probably, that's about right.
You can see that everything has been mixed all the way through.
There's no lightener or color separated.
It's all mixed pretty good.
If you shake it too much, it actually heats up the molecules and speeds up the color process.
So, it doesn't process properly.
So, just a light shake.
Make sure that cover, that hole is covered.
And, now we're ready to apply color.